孩子们 2008年的秋天\n我出了点小问题
Kids,in the fall of 2008,I\nhad a little problem.
好了 我要去Stella家了
All right,I got to get to Stella's.
就是今晚了 伙计们
Tonight's the night,guys.
我以前也试过 可每次都失败
I've tried it before,I've\nfailed every time.
这次 我一定要成功
This time,I am gonna do it.
今晚...
Tonight...
我要钓个拉拉
I pick up a lesbian.
Robin 借你唇膏一用
Robin,I need your lipstick.
噢 不是吧!
Oh,man!
记得拍照
Take pictures,all right?
辣吧
Spicy.
我住在纽约 \n可Stella住在河那边的新泽西
I lived in New York,but Stella lived\nacross the river in New Jersey...
噢 不是吧!
Oh,man!
也就是说我一直在坐火车
which meant I was\nalways taking the train.
你好吗 Ted?
What's up,Ted?
嘿 Matisse
Hey,Matisse.
- 嘿 T老弟!
- Theodore!\n- Hey,T-Diddy!\n- Theodore!
你错过了
You missed it.
Robin赚到那份国家台主播的工作了
Robin got that national anchor job.
我们赚了一瓶免费香槟
And we got a free bottle of champagne.
不过已经喝光光了
Ah,but it's empty now.
噢 不是吧!
Oh,man!
结果是 我好像什么都错过了
And as result,it seemed like I\nwas missing out on everything.
不好意思 没等你 饭菜都凉了
Sorry,we couldn't wait.\nIt was getting cold.
不是吧!
Oh,man!
- 嘿 傻大个\n- 怎么了 小丫头?
- Hey,big guy.\n- What's up,G?
你没事吧?
Are you okay?
嗯 我没事 只是...
Yeah,I'm fine. It's just...
我想跟你们在一起
you know,I want to\nhang out with you guys.
也想跟我的朋友们在一起
I want to hang out with my friends.
可我的时间基本上都花在了火车上
I just feel like I'm spending\nall my time on the train.
OK 这样如何 改天你把你朋友\n都请到这儿来玩吧?
Okay,how about this,why don't you ask\nyour friends to come out here sometime?
好主意
That's a great idea.
你想让我们去新泽西?  太有才了
You want us to go to New\nJersey? Oh,that is rich.
怎么了?
Why?
呃...首先 我的那些\n金闪闪的夸张服饰早就不在了
Well,for starters,I don't have\nany of my gold medallions anymore.
在它们八百年前过气的时候\n我就给卖了
I sold them when they went\nout of style 400 years ago.
Lily?\nLily?
抱歉 Ted
Oh,sorry,Ted.
我是土生土长的纽约人
I'm a born and raised New Yorker.
我已经形成了"轻视厌恶新泽西及\n其所代表事物"的思维模式
I'm programmed to despise and loathe\nNew Jersey and all that it stands for.
我跟你解释这么多干嘛?
Why am I telling you this?
你比任何人都要厌恶新泽西
You hate New Jersey more than anyone.
什么? 我才不厌恶新泽西\n你怎么会这么想?
What? I don't hate New Jersey.\nWhy would you think that?
他就这样插我队
And then he cut in front of me.
上帝 我恨插队的\n比我恨新泽西还厉害
God,I hate line cutters\nmore than I hate New Jersey.
不对 没什么能胜过\n我对新泽西的厌恶
Well,that's not true. There's\nnothing I hate more than New Jersey.
是吧
Right?
嘿 要我们等你吗?
Hey,you want us to wait for you?
不用了 我可能还要一会儿吧
No,I might be awhile.
我得把新泽西废物排泄干净
I got a drop a massive New Jersey.
好吧 新泽西不是我最喜欢的地方
Okay,so New Jersey's\nnot my favorite place.
可只要Stella跟我结婚后\n她跟Lucy就可以搬来跟我住
But once Stella and I get married\nand she and Lucy move in with me,
我就再也不踏入新泽西半步
I'll never set foot in New Jersey again.
除非去看巨人队比赛 或者坐飞机去\n纽瓦克 或者去看God Forbid乐队演出\n再不然就是去那里弃尸...
Unless I'm going to see a Giants game or flying\nout of Newark or God forbid,disposing of a body.
Ted 如果你杀了我 然后又把我埋在新泽西\n我做鬼也不会放过你的
Ted,if you murder me and bury me in\nNew Jersey,I'll haunt you forever.
要是我杀了你 把你埋在别的地方呢?
But if I murder you and\nbury you somewhere else?
那就算了吧
Eh,I'll leave you alone.
我想你肯定是有原因的
I'm sure you had your reasons.
How I Met\nYour Mother Season04 Episode03
孩子们 你们的Robin阿姨厌倦了\n在地铁新闻一台的工作
=,your Aunt Robin was sick\nof her job at Metro News One.
厌倦了恶劣的工作环境...
She was sick of the\nlow production value...
我是Robin Scherbatsky  \n你们正在收看的是...
I'm Robin Scherbatsky,and\nyou're watching...
"地道"新闻一台11点节目
Etro News One at 11:00.
不对 是1点
And again at 1:00.
厌倦了每天要读的新闻...
sick of the stories she had to report...
那么赶快来为纽约\n最可爱的狗狗投上一票吧
So hurry up and get your votes\nin for New York's cutest doggie.
最重要的是 \n厌倦了那些愚蠢的双关语
and most of all,she was\nsick of all the stupid puns.
由于地铁脱轨 \n四名运输工人当场毙命
Four transit workers were electrocuted\nwhen a subway train jumped the tracks.
敬请期待下面...
Stay tuned for the...
惊人的出轨\n(derail出轨与detail细节音近)
shocking derails.
Joel 死人了诶 有点同情心好不好
Joel,people died.
当她接到国家电视台的录用通知之后
So when the call came in that she\ngot the big national anchor job,
她终于能够说那些\n她多年以来想说的话了...
she finally got to say the words she'd\nbeen dreaming of saying for years...
今晚将是我最后一次播报新闻
Tonight will be my last broadcast.
我还是个黄毛丫头的时候\n就来了地铁新闻一台
I came to Metro News One\nas a little caterpillar.
四年过去了 这张桌子就像我的茧
And for four years,this\ndesk has been my cocoon.
不过今晚 我要破茧而出了
But tonight,I emerge\nan ambitious butterfly.
她怎么听起来像个傻子?\n脑袋撞墙了?
Why does she sound like an\nidiot? Did she have a stroke?
是啊 灵光一现的一撞
Yeah. A stroke of genius.
这个演讲太棒了
This speech is really good.
一眼看着地平线 一眼看着真相
With one eye on the\nhorizon,one eye on the truth,
一眼看着你们大家
and one eye on all of you.
你给她写的 对不对?
You wrote it for her,didn't you?
这是我之前因为慢性耳膜炎
It's a modified version\nof the speech I gave
不得不退出游泳队时演讲的修订版
when I had to leave the swim team\nbecause of a chronic inner ear situation.
你不是在游泳队打杂的吗?
I thought you were the towel boy.
那也是团队一员
It's part of the team.
所以周六 就在Robin换工作后\n第一天上班的时候
So that Saturday as Robin went off\nfor her first day at her new job,
我们一行人越过大河去体验\n疯狂的新泽西夜生活
we all headed across the river to experience\nsome of that crazy New Jersey nightlife.
OK Stella找不到保姆 \n所以我们没法出门了 不如...
Okay,Stella couldn't find a\nsitter,so we can't go out. Instead...
我们就呆在这儿 \n我想会一样好玩的
we're all gonna hang out here\nand it's gonna be just as awesome.
没错 可以玩棋盘游戏 可以看电影
Right,we got board games,we got movies.
我想车库里应该也有点啤酒
And I think there may be\nsome beer out in the garage.
Ted 这太可悲了\n这可是大周六晚上
Ted,this is pathetic.\nIt's Saturday night.
我们应该在酒吧 大口喝酒的
We should be out at a\nbar. drinking alcohol.
我知道这么说你会很郁闷 伤心\n不过这就是事实
Now I know that that sounds depressing,bordering\non tragic,but it's just a fact.
没错 我还想再调戏调戏\n那个叫Doris的妞呢
Yeah,and I want another\ncrack at that chick,Doris.
我一定能坐上那个拉拉的飞机的
I know I can land that lesbian plane.
那飞机上肯定没别的"鸟"了
No snakes on that plane.
OK 伙计们 别这样 你们答应了的
Okay,guys. Come on,you promised.
我们就呆在这儿吧 尽量开心点
Let's just hang out\nhere,try to have fun.
我们都在啊 朋友们一起玩玩
I mean,we're all\ntogether,friends hanging out.
这个不是最重要的吗?
Isn't that what really matters?
OK 如果我们赶下一趟车\n能在11点前赶到MacLaren
Okay,if we take the next train,we\ncan be at MacLaren's by 11:00.
可能10点就到了
We can be there by 10:00.
不 我得换身衣服
No,I have to change first.
我才不想沾满一身新泽西味地\n跑到MacLaren去
I am not walking into MacLaren's\nsmelling like New Jersey.
你们很讨厌这儿 对吗?
You guys really hate it here,huh?
什么? 才没有 Stels...
What? No! Stels...
我明白 你们都是纽约人嘛
I get it,I mean,you\nguys are all New Yorkers.
你们得去酒吧消遣
You need to go hang out at a bar.
你们可以到全州最酷的酒吧逛逛\n绝对会让你们大跌眼镜的
Well,you could just hang out at the coolest bar in\nthe state,which is so close it will blow your mind.
瞧好了 您咧
And boom goes the dynamite.
新泽西最酷的酒吧
The coolest bar in New Jersey.
是啊 可能吧
Yeah,it probably is.
棒极了! 有飞镖
This is great! We got darts.
半个乒乓球桌  一整个鱼缸
Half a ping-pong table. A fish bowl.
瞧瞧 答应你们的超级一夜 \n没让你们失望吧
Look what turned out to be\nan awesome night as promised.
也许我们能扔点培根进去\n看看它们打架
Maybe we can drop some Bac-O's\nin here and make them fight.
不用了吧 我从来不对鱼感兴趣\n除了两类我最喜欢的鱼--
No,thanks.I don't mess with fish bowls\nunless they have my two favorite fish--
"吸鱼"跟"吹鱼"
the sucker fish and the blow fish.
说得好吧!
What up!
"吹鱼"?
For "blow fish"?
不觉得
I don't think so.
- Marshall
- 你水平不该这么差的
- Marshall.\n- You're better than that.
- Lily
- 不够好
- Lily.\n- Not good enough.
Stella?\nStella?
抱歉
Sorry.
在没人给我尊重跟我闪亮一击之前
I am not lowering this until\nsomeone gives me the respect
我是不会把手放下来的
of another person's knuckles tapping\nagainst mine in a light but decisive manner.
来嘛 来嘛...\n来嘛 小宝贝
Pretty,pretty... Pretty,pretty...\nPretty... Who's a pretty baby?
那好吧 再听着...
Then know this...
在他得到想要的东西...不对...\n是应得的东西之前
until it gets what\nit wants,nay,deserves,
这个拳头绝不妥协
this fist will not yield.
绝-不-妥-协
It. Will. Not. Yield.
- 谁想玩拼字游戏?\n- 好啊
- So who wants to play Scrabble?\n- Sure,whatever.
对了 "X"形状的拼板有点看不清
Oh,heads up,the "X" tile is little\nhard to read because a couple years ago,
因为几年前我的狗特别"青睐"过
it went all the way through my dog.
也许等你搬进来后我们再养条狗
You know,maybe we should get\na dog again when you move in.
我什么?
When I what?
哦 太好了 是Robin来了
Oh,great. There's Robin.
我以为她们会搬去跟你住
I thought they were moving in with you.
我也是
So did I.
噢 上帝 我要搬来新泽西?
Oh,God,am I moving to New Jersey?
嘿 伙计们 我打赌那狗吞下"X"之后\n肯定很嗨
Hey,guys,I bet that dog was really flying\nhigh after it swallowed a little "X."
酷毙了!
Nailed it!
不是吧!
Come on!
我不能在这儿住
I can't live here.
也许没那么糟呢
It wouldn't be that bad.
你能在那摆个迷你冰箱\n还能玩玩小型曲棍球
You could put a mini\n- fridge over there and maybe some knock hockey.
小型曲棍球 好样的 来一个
Knock hockey. Nice one,Big Mon.
我是说整个新泽西 不是这个地下室
I meant New Jersey in\ngeneral,not this basement.
她想让我搬来? 我糊涂了\n几个月前我们谈过
She wants me to move here? I don't\nget it. We discussed this months ago.
我在想我们结婚以后\n你跟Lucy可以搬过来
So I was thinking after the\nwedding,you and Lucy could move in here.
当然了 她可以在救生梯那玩
Yeah,she could play\nout on the fire escape,
也可以跟那个在后巷\n睡在沙发上的人交朋友
maybe make friends with that guy who\nsleeps on that couch in the alley,
骑着自行车去百老汇
ride her bike up and down Broadway.
主意棒极了 Ted
It's a great idea,Ted.
想不明白有机会住在曼哈顿
I don't understand why you'd\nwant to live in New Jersey
干嘛非要留在新泽西
when you have a chance\nto live in Manhattan?
我原以为在上西区有套\n租金固定的公寓
I thought having a rent-controlled\napartment on the Upper West Side
是她答应嫁给我的部分原因
was half the reason\nshe agreed to marry me.
是吗 我以为是全部原因呢?\n这个不错吧
Really,I thought it was the\nwhole reason. What is up?
Robin 嘿! 看起来不错哦
Robin,hey! Looking good.
撞一个
Bump the Barnacle.
Stella让我别
Stella already told me not to.
你第一天如何?
How was your first day?
- 不是\n- 什么?
- It wasn't.\n- What?
不是我的第一天
It wasn't my first day.
我到那儿去发现还有其他20个人
I showed up and there\nwere 20 other people.
看样子我还没有拿到那份工作
It turns out,I didn't\nactually get the job.
他们只是让我去试镜
I only got an audition.
什么 怎么会这样?
What,how did that happen?
我不知道 因为他们告诉我成功了啊
I don't know. Because\nhe told me that I got it.
我成功了? 我成功了!
I got it? I got it!
得说清楚 我说"你成功了" \n指的是试镜机会
And just to be clear,when I say\n"you got it," I mean an audition.
你成功得到了试镜机会
You got an audition.
我不想有任何误会 你得到的只是试镜
I don't want there to be any\nconfusion. You have an audition only.
不是这份工作
Not the job.
谢谢! 谢谢!
Thank you! Thank you!
好了 我现在要给Joel打电话 \n让我回去
Okay,I'm going to call and beg\nJoel to give me my job back.
- 别!\n- 你讨厌那份工作
- No!\n- You hated that job.
不知道 也没那么糟吧
I don't know,it wasn't so bad.
Robin 外面下着磅礴大雨的时候\n他们让你管热带风暴叫啥?
Robin,what did they make you call Tropical\nStorm Hector when it was raining cats and dogs?
"热风雨"
A furricane.
嘿 Ted 像"热风雨"一样震撼我
Hey,Ted. Rock me like a furricane.
谢了
Thanks.
还真忍心...
Mean.
OK 是的 糟透了 可我能怎么办?
Okay,yeah,it sucks,but what can I do?
我没法拿到那份工作的
I mean,I'm not going\nto get that other job.
你们得去看看去试镜的那些女人
You guys should have seen the\nother women at this audition.
个个比我有经验 比我有特色
They all had more experience\nthan me,were more ethnic than me.
居然有个长着蓝眼睛的非裔美国小妞\n我能比得上吗?
There was an African-American chick with\nblue eyes,how can I compete with that?
确实不能
Mm,you can't.
不 你能胜过任何人
No,you can compete with anyone.
你是Robin Scherbatsky
You're Robin Scherbatsky.
自信 强硬 高挑
Confident. Strong. Tall.
还有穿上短裤让人惊羡的美腿
With crazy long legs\nthat look great in shorts.
我要打给Joel
I'm calling Joel.
不 Robin 如果你现在给他打电话\n你会后悔的
No,Robin,if you call him right\nnow,you will hate yourself.
听着 我跟很多女人睡过\n之后有些人会消失
Look,I have slept with lots of women who\nafterwards told me off and stormed out.
但是有时候又会拿起电话打给我\n我们会再勾搭上
And sometimes they'd pick up the phone and\nthey'd call me and then we'd hook up again.
完事之后 我能看到她们的表情
And when we were finished,I could\nsee that look on their faces,
那是厌恶自己 \n后悔不该打电话的表情
that look that says they hate themselves\nand they wish they'd never called.
如果你能看到那表情...
But if you could see that look...
实际上 你能看到 有个视频\n在www.....
Actually,you can see that\nlook,there's a video. www-dot...
别说了! 好了! 我不打就是
No! Stop,okay? I won't call.
别喝那啤酒!
Don't drink the beer!
我刚想起来是啥时候买的
I just remembered when I bought it.
是在我怀Lucy之前买的
It was right before I\ngot pregnant with Lucy.
Ted 能不能去趟PriceCo买点回来?
Ted,would you mind running to\nPriceCo and picking some up?
你到了那 也许该申请个会员卡
Oh,and while you're there,maybe\nyou could sign up for a card.
你可能会经常去那里的
I mean,you'll probably end\nup going there all the time.
就是这个表情
That's the look.
我不能搬来这里 我讨厌这 我会自杀的
I can't move here. I hate\nit here. I would kill myself.
也许新泽西也没那么糟  \nStella有块草坪
Maybe New Jersey's not\nthat bad. Stella has a lawn.
你可以玩割草机 那边就有卖的
You could get a riding lawn\nmower. They sell them over there.
我还看到有杯托
I saw one with a cup holder.
我还看到一个带杯托的躺椅
I saw a recliner with\na built-in cup holder.
我甚至还看到了带杯托的吊床
I even saw a hammock with a cup holder.
要是你住在新泽西  \n就再也不用手举着杯子了
You live in New Jersey,you\nnever have to hold a cup again.
我还真不像你似的对 \n举杯子有那么大障碍
I don't think I have as big a\nproblem holding cups as you do.
你跟我碰下拳 我给你100块
I will give you $100 to fist pump me.
200块
放下来吧 Barney
Just put it down,Barney.
你现在胳膊一定疼死了
Your arm must be killing you by now.
1万块如何
瞧 你只是刚好在河对岸 \n你随时能到纽约的
Look,you'll be right across the river.\nYou'll be in New York all the time.
- 真的么?\n- 真的
- Oh,yeah?\n- Yeah.
打扰一下
Um,excuse me.
你们是从纽约搬来的吧
You guys are from New York,right?
对 我们从曼哈顿搬来
Yeah,we moved here from Manhattan.
你们进过城吗
Do you ever get into the city?
随时都能进
All the time.
听见了没 随时都能进
See? All the time.
那上次进城是什么时候?
When was the last time you were there?
我们刚在O'Rourke吃过晚饭
We just had dinner at O'Rourke's.
那地方已经关了6年了
That's been closed for six years.
那还真是有阵子了
It has been awhile.
有趣 我们都没发现
Funny,we don't miss it.
我想我们现在已经完全变成新泽西人了
Well,I guess we're New Jersey-ians now.
亲爱的 瞧 狗狗T恤
Honey,look,dog shirts.
我不能这样
I can't do it.
我要告诉Stella 她和Lucy该搬去纽约
I'm just going to tell Stella she and Lucy\nhave to move into the city and that's that.
你们觉得哪件好?
MARSHALL: Okay,what do you guys think?
小猎犬还是波士顿狗?
Beagle or Boston terrier?
你眼中是泪水吗?
Are those tears?
是勇敢的男儿泪水 不带感情的
They're awesome... manly pain\ntears. They're not emotional.
好吧 稍稍有些感情在里面
Okay,they're a little bit emotional.
Robin在哪?
Where's Robin?
哦 不!
Oh,no.
嘿 Shirley 我是Robin 要找Joel
Hey,Shirley,it's Robin calling for Joel.
Robin 挂掉电话 别这样
Robin,hang up the phone. Don't do this.
对不起 我明白
Sorry,I know,okay?
- 如果你现在不挂电话... \n- 别说了
- If you don't hang up right now...\n- Stop.
嘿 Joel 我是Robin
Hey,Joel,it's Robin.
蝴蝶夫人想飞回茧里面来
So Madam Butterfly wants\nto come back to the cocoon.
听着 说了那样的话 我很抱歉
Yeah,look,I'm sorry\nI said all that stuff.
道歉的话留着对家里装袜子的抽屉说去吧 \n因为你已经被顶替了
Well,you can stick your sorries in your sock\ndrawer,'cause you've already been replaced.
Brian在这里精心化妆 他已经无比激动了
I've got Brian in makeup and\nhe couldn't be more excited.
我不行 我不行
I can't do this. I can't do this.
好吧 我可不想见到一个大学生\n在镜头前汗流浃背
Uh,okay,look,as much as I want to see\ncollege boy here wet himself on camera,
如果你能及时赶回来播报11点新闻 \n你就能保住饭碗
if you can get here in time to read the\n11:00 news,you can have your old job back.
好 我有半个钟头赶到电台
Okay,I have a half hour\nto make it to the studio.
你不可能半个小时赶到那里
There's no way you can make\nit to the city in a half hour.
Robin 别这样
Robin,don't do this.
我知道自己赌一把很让人害怕 \n但如果你不赌 没人会为你赌
I know it's scary to bet on yourself,but\nif you don't,nobody else will.
我这么说不是为了要碰拳
And I'm not just saying\nthat to get a fist bump.
尽管碰个拳也挺好 但我是说真的
Although,come on,a fist bump would\nbe great. But I really mean it.
我正是要自己赌一把
I am betting on myself.
我赌自己能在11点赶回去
I am betting that I can\nmake it there by 11:00.
买到啤酒了吗?
Hey,did you get the beer?
我买了144罐一组的
Yeah,I got 144-pack.
剩下的在后备箱
The rest is in the trunk.
办会员卡了吗?
And did you sign up for the membership?
没有
No.
为啥呢
Why not?
照相排好长的队...而且我的发型一团糟
There was a line for the\nphotos... my hair's a mess...
我不想搬来新泽西
I don't want to move to New Jersey.
什么?
What?
我不能这样
I can't do it.
我也想不出你和Lucy留在这里的理由
And I can't see any reason why you\nand Lucy shouldn't move to New York.
我女儿在这边上学
Well,my daughter goes to school here.
她的朋友全都在这里
All of her friends are here.
我一辈子都住在这里 我的全家都在这
I've lived here my whole\nlife. My whole family is here.
这是我的房子 我是家庭教师协会一份子
This is my house. I'm on the PTA.
等到6月1号 我就是副会长了
And as of June 1,I'm the deputy mayor.
没错 但我的公寓离地铁很近
Yes,but my apartment is\nreally close to the subway.
Ted 我们不会搬的 讨论结束
Ted,we're not moving,end of discussion.
如果没有讨论过 哪来的讨论结束呢
How can it be end of discussion\nif there's never been a discussion?
这就是为人父母的一部分 \n我不能改变Lucy的生活
This is part of being a parent.\nI can't just uproot Lucy.
带着孩子的父母一直都搬来搬去的
People with kids move all the time.
我想对Lucy来说 在世界数一数二的\n大城市里成长再好不过
I think it would be really great for Lucy\nto grow up in the greatest city in the world.
又来了--纽约是世界上数一数二的大城市
Oh,here we go-- New York's the\ngreatest city in the whole wide world.
在这里美梦成真 \n就连鸽子的便便味道都像木薯粉
It's where dreams come true and\npigeon poop tastes like tapioca.
想知道个小秘密吗 Ted
Want to know a little secret,Ted?
新泽西比纽约更好
New Jersey is better than New York.
更好...你认为...我...
Better than... You think... I...
帝国大厦...
The Empire State Buil...
H&H百吉饼店...
H and H Bage...
林肯中心... 休闲酒吧... \n木瓜大王热狗店
Lincoln Ce... Zabar's... Papaya King.
纽约就是地球上知识与文化的结合之所
New York is the intellectual\nand cultural hub of the planet.
纽约全是怪人 尽是些谄媚和刻薄之人
New York is full of weirdoes,and\nsnobs and mean people.
Ted 知道有次一个老妇人骂我婊子 \n还把猫扔我脸上吗?
Ted,do you know that once,an old lady actually\ncalled me a bitch and threw a cat in my face?
想知道这种事有没有在新泽西发生过吗
And you want to know if\nthat happened in New Jersey?
没有 Lex大街86号 刚好发生在\n你最爱的木瓜大王热狗店门前
Uh-uh,86th and Lex,right in front\nof your beloved little Papaya King.
Ted 新泽西的人很友好
Ted,people are nice in New Jersey.
在这里你可以结识你的邻居
I mean it's the kind of place\nwhere you know your neighbors.
嘿 我和我的邻居很熟
Hey,I know my neighbors.
是吗 比如谁?
Oh,yeah? Like who?
就对门的 我认识...
Right across the hall,I got...
Clax... pa... mon...\nClax... pa... mon...
Claxpamon?\nClaxpamon?
人家叫Paxton
His name is Paxton.
我最喜欢他了
Love that dude.
抱歉 赶时间 要到前面去 请让开
Sorry,in a hurry. Got to get to\nthe front. Got to get off first.
别撞到Matisse
Whoa,don't run over Matisse.
有没有搞错
Okay,so this is crazy.
你不该认为新泽西比纽约好
You can't actually think that New\nJersey is better than New York.
纽约有百老汇 凭这点我们就赢了
New York has Broadway.\nWe win right there.
不 她没有 碰一下以策安全
Oh,no,she did not.\nKnuckle up for safety.
我们有大西洋城
We have Atlantic City.
无法超越的大西洋城 \n靓女碰下吧 没人知道的
Can't beat the A.C. Pretty\nplease? No one has to know.
纽约有格林威治村
New York has Greenwich Village.
新泽西有The Shore乐队
New Jersey has The Shore.
纽约有Woody Allen
Woody Allen.
荣获奥斯卡奖的都市传奇人物 来吧
Oscar-winning chronicler\nof urban neuroses. Bump it!
Bruce Springsteen\nBruce Springsteen.
Sinatra\nSinatra.
他是霍博肯出身...属新泽西
He's from Hoboken... New Jersey.
没错 但他唱的是什么城市来着
Yeah,but what city is he singing about?
不是"锡考克斯镇 锡考克斯镇"吧
It's not "Secaucus,Secaucus."
孩子们 不管你们相信与否
Now you kids can either\nbelieve this or not,
Robin阿姨是这样完成自己的誓言的
but this is how your Aunt\nRobin swears it happened.
听着 Stella 我明白从新泽西来的你\n无法想象自己会热爱纽约
Look,Stella,I understand that coming from New\nJersey you don't picture yourself loving New York,
但请相信我 Marshall一开始也不相信 \n但现在他都不愿意住在别处
but trust me,Marshall didn't expect to,and\nnow he wouldn't think of living anywhere else.
我讨厌纽约!
I hate New York!
对不起 但是真的
I'm sorry,but it's true.
今天我去PriceCo
Okay,today I was walking around PriceCo.
你去过吗 里面超大的
Have you ever been there? It's huge.
纽约所有店铺都那么窄
All the stores in New\nYork are so cramped.
每次我转身都要碰掉东西
Every time I turn,I\nknock something over.
我就像从海里来的大怪兽 \n一心想毁掉酒窖似的
I'm like some huge monster that came\nout of the ocean to destroy bodegas.
但是Marshall 你是爱纽约的
But,Marshall,you love New York.
是的 但我更恨它
Yeah,I do,except that I hate it.
我对纽约来说块头太大了
I'm too big for New York,okay?
我总要努力挤进窄小的地铁座位
I'm always trying to fit into\ncramped little subway seats
或者低头躲建了150年之久的大门
or duck under doorways that\nwere built 150 years ago.
知道吗 现在人们块头都大了 \n弄个大点的门
Hey,guess what? People are\nbigger now. Build bigger doorways.
你们这帮人是怎么了
What the hell is the matter with you?
小城市 大块头-- 来一下
Small city,big\nman-- give it up.
而且那里还很吵闹 一刻不停
And it's so loud,all the time.
那是座不眠之城
Yes,it's the city that never sleeps.
但你猜怎么着 我就喜欢睡觉
Well,guess what,I like to sleep.
我累了8年了
I've been tired for eight years.
我厌倦了因为钻矮子的门口\n而把自己手肘弄得青一块紫一块
Tired and scared with black and blue marks on my elbows\nfrom trying to fit through all these tiny elf doorways.
新泽西就很好
New Jersey's great.
大商店 草坪 而且还不用自己举杯子
It's got huge stores,and lawns and\nyou never have to carry a cup again.
这辈子都不用
Not for the rest of your life.
我要无所畏惧的高呼--我爱新泽西
I'm not afraid to say\nit-- I love New Jersey.
我开玩笑呢
I'm just kidding.
听着 Stella...
Look,Stella...
我明白
I get it,okay?
我懂你意思
I see what you're saying.
我想...
I guess...
我们可以住在布鲁克林区 \n(纽约贫民区)
we could live in Brooklyn.
知道吗 Ted...
You know what,Ted...
你爱住哪住哪 我管不着
live wherever you want. I don't care.
尴尬的沉默 碰一下
Awkward silence. Tap it.
嘿 Lucy 起来干嘛
Oh,hey,Lucy. What are you doing up?
地下室很吵
There was some loud\nnoises in the basement.
真抱歉
Sorry about that.
干嘛不回去睡觉呢 亲爱的
Why don't you got back to bed,sweetie.
不听故事 我睡不着
I can't go to sleep without a story.
- 好 我去给你找妈妈... \n- 你能念给我听吗
- Okay,I'll just get your mom...\n- Why don't you read it to me?
好 来吧
Okay,come on.
* You know she thrills me with all her charms *\n* You know she thrills\nme with all her charms *
* When I'm wrapped up in my baby's arms *\n* When I'm wrapped\nup in my baby's arms *
* My little girl gives me everything *\n* My little girl gives me everything *
* When I'm walking down the street with you *\n* When I'm walking down\nthe street with you *
* Sing sha-la-la,la-la-la-la Sha-la-la-la...*\n* Sing sha-la-la,la-la-la-la\nSha-la-la-la...*
我搬来这边
I'm moving here.
- 真的吗? \n- 真的
- Really?\n- Really.
新泽西胜出
New Jersey wins.
谢谢
Oh,thank you!
等下...
Wait...
晚上好 纽约
Good evening,New York.
瞧 她赶到了
Hey,look,she made it.
今晚的头条是 在中央动物园出生的\n熊猫宝宝刚长出了第一颗牙
Our top story tonight-- the newborn panda at\nthe Central Park Zoo got its first tooth today.
我想它变成了...
I guess that makes her a...
臼齿熊
molar bear.
臼齿熊 臼齿熊
Molar bear. Molar bear.
知道吗 我还是算了
You know what? I really am done.
晚安 纽约
Good night,New York.
她真的辞职了
Wow,she really quit.
你觉得这事和我们有关系吗
You think we had\nanything to do with that?
是啊 我想有的
Yeah,I think we did.
干得漂亮 Barney
Nice job,Barney.
额滴神啊 谢谢
Oh,my God! Thank you!
我的胳膊简直疼死了
Oh,that was killing my arm.
上次这么酸疼还是我13岁\n想把浴室的门锁上的时候呢
My arm hasn't been this sore since I was 13\nyears old and figured out how to lock a bathroom.
击掌
Up top.
哦 不
Oh,no.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
我最终与那份工作无缘
Well,I officially didn't get that job.
我很遗憾
I'm so sorry.
没关系 他们提供了另一份工作
That's okay. They,um,they\noffered me another one.
好极了 那你要做什么
Hey,that's great. What\nare you going to be doing?
海外通讯记者 我...
Foreign correspondent. I'm,uh...
要去日本了
moving to Japan.